# **Nicholas Platt**

Software Engineer

■ Annapolis Junction, MD
■ (909) 293-8750
☑ nick@nickplatt.dev
Ⅲ TS//SCI with FS Poly

#### Introduction

Experienced software engineer and technical writer with professional work in front-end development, creating user-focused documentation, and working directly with multiple development teams. Familiar with working within a Linux environment. Extremely eager for learning and mentorship. Currently working towards a master's degree in Software Engineering.

#### **Education**

#### University Of Maryland Global Campus | 2016 - 2020

BS Computer Networking & Cyber Security - 3.8 GPA

#### University Of Maryland Global Campus | 2021 - Present

MS Software Engineering – 4.0 GPA – Expected Graduation: 2023

## **Experience**

## Boeing Intelligence & Analytics (BI&A)

August 2018 - Present

#### Software Engineer

May 2021 - Present

- Worked within an Agile environment developing web applications using the following technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, AngulaJS, MongoDB, and Apache Maven.
- Improved UI/UX design through miscellaneous front-end development, ensuring that compliance needs were met for users with disabilities.
- Utilized Git to manage the version control of different repositories of data.
- Created Swagger documentation from the ground up for interactive API documentation for integrators.
- Answered user questions through JIRA and created help tickets to track fixes for future cases.
- Created scripts to alter data stored within MongoDB.
- Directly worked with customer requests to build new features in software.
- Tested new features before release to users to ensure operability and document any issues/bugs.

#### Technical Writer III

August 2018 – May 2021

- Created, edited, modified, and compiled over 2,000 pages of tool documentation (within Confluence) to give analysts a resource to refer to with questions on how a specific tool functions and the capabilities available within the tool.
- Worked directly with developers to learn the latest features and functionalities of the tools to better assist customers.
- Assisted in the creation and updating of learning materials to help train users how to take advantage of available features in the tool, ranging from basic introductions to advanced workflows.
- Tested new features before release to production, while reporting bugs and suggestions directly to developers.
- Assisted with proposal writings for multimillion-dollar contracts, focusing on grammar and style compliance.

#### **United States Marine Corps (USMC)**

## **August 2013 – August 2018**

#### ELINT Analyst (MOS: 2631)

- Delivered full electromagnetic spectrum reporting of target electromagnetic space to enable combatant commanders to develop an operational course of action as part of the E-Space Analysis Center program.
- Successfully briefed, deploying units, and interested offices, the capabilities offered by the E-Space Analysis Center.
- Maintained the office's Confluence space with relevant notes and request procedures for users.
- Efficiently arranged and participated in the analysis, processing, and distribution of strategic and tactical intelligence.
- Created detailed analytic products including radio spectrum analysis and GSM network intelligence that enabled various tactical actions including target exploitation, SIGINT mission support, and force protection measures.
- Worked closely with customers, tailoring reports to meet their standards and requirements.
- Completed and collaborated on over 200 serialized reports, utilizing multiple secure databases and tools while maintaining 100% compliance.

#### Skills

Programming Languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Java, Python, Markdown

**Documentation Tools** Confluence, MKDocs, Sphinx, Hugo

Frameworks Angular, Express, React

Misc. Tools Github, Gitlab, Atlassian Jira/Confluence, Jenkins

# **Personal Projects**

**Soccerfront.io** - Soccerfront is a soccer live score web application built using Nodejs, ExpressJS, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Soccerfront pulls data from the API-FOOTBALL API and displays the information in an easy-to-use live score table and league table (standings) view. Currently, over 20 leagues/cups are supported! This is an ongoing project and new features will be added sporadically. Hosted on a DigitalOcean droplet running Linux and NGINX. - <a href="https://soccerfront.io">https://soccerfront.io</a>

**Personal Documentation Website -** A fully searchable and robust documentation site built using Material for MKDocs and written in Markdown. Multiple additional JavaScript modules, such as an image light gallery and scroll-to-top button added. Created to help facilitate personal learning and retain all information from books and classes attended. Hosted on a DigitalOcean droplet running Linux and Apache - <a href="https://docs.nicklyss.com">https://docs.nicklyss.com</a>